[{"question":" ______  cut the stems into strips, pressed them, and dried them into sheets that could be rolled into scrolls.","options":["Algerian","Bantu","Egyptians","Angolan"],"extras":["Basotho","Beninese","Berber","Black African"],"answer":"Egyptians"},{"question":"As in many ancient societies, much of the knowledge of  ______  came about as priests studied the world to find ways to please the gods.","options":[{},"Egypt"],"extras":[],"answer":"Egypt"},{"question":"About 5,000 years ago, they noticed that a star now called Sirius appeared shortly before the  ______  began to flood.","options":[{},"Nile"],"extras":[],"answer":"Nile"},{"question":"The  ______  meant “great house,” and it was originally used to describe the king’s palace.","options":["Word pharaoh",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Word pharaoh"},{"question":"About 80 years later, a  ______  named Khufu decided he wanted a monument that would show the world how great he was.","options":["Caliph","Bourbon","Pharaoh","Basileus"],"extras":["Dictator","Dynast","Emir","Ethnarch"],"answer":"Pharaoh"},{"question":"About 80  ______  later, a pharaoh named Khufu decided he wanted a monument that would show the world how great he was.","options":["Years","Air Alert","Bimester","Bimillennium"],"extras":["Bout","Bronze Age","Calendar Day","Calendar Month"],"answer":"Years"},{"question":"The word pharaoh meant “great house,” and it was originally used to describe the  ______ ’s palace.","options":["Czar","King","Carolingian","Capetian"],"extras":["Emperor","Merovingian","Shah"],"answer":"King"},{"question":"Mourners filled the  ______  with objects ranging from food to furniture that the mummified pharaoh would need.","options":["Grave","Birthplace","End","Tomb"],"extras":["Hiding Place","High","Hole-in-the-wall","Holy Place"],"answer":"Tomb"},{"question":"Before entering a temple, a  ______  bathed and put on special linen garments and white sandals.","options":["Anagnost","Acolyte","Archdeacon","Priest"],"extras":["Chaplain","Cleric","Curate","Deacon"],"answer":"Priest"},{"question":"Cities emerge as centers of culture and power, and  ______  learn to do jobs that do not involve agriculture.","options":["Actinoid","Arrangement","People","Association"],"extras":["Biological Group","Circuit","Citizenry","Collection"],"answer":"People"},{"question":"A city called Giza was built for the  ______  workers and the people who fed, clothed, and housed them.","options":["Pyramid",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Pyramid"},{"question":" ______ , Black Land The ancient Egyptians lived in narrow bands of land on each side of the Nile.","options":["Red land",{}],"extras":[],"answer":"Red land"},{"question":"As in many ancient societies, much of the knowledge of Egypt came about as priests studied the world to find ways to please the  ______ .","options":[{},"Gods"],"extras":[],"answer":"Gods"},{"question":"Unlike the Tigris and Euphrates, the  ______  flooded at the same time every year, so farmers could predict when to plant their crops.","options":[{},"Nile river"],"extras":[],"answer":"Nile river"},{"question":"These beautiful blue  ______  were used in jewelry.The Nile had fish and other wildlife that Egyptians wanted.","options":["Stones","Half Pound","Grain","Dram"],"extras":["Hundredweight","Kiloton","Long Ton","Megaton"],"answer":"Stones"}]